(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T17:32:26.124943",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
硬すぎたのかな、ビンが
Was it too hard, the bottle?
あるいは船首だけ柔いか
Or is only the bow soft?
延命した赤ワインは延々、波の上
Life-extended red wine endlessly on the waves,
拾い、飲むのは中毒患者
Picked up and drunk by an addict.
広い空なのに奇妙な予感だ
Despite the wide sky, a strange premonition.
ああ、そうか簡単だ、船長を決めてなかったんだ
Ah, I see, it's simple, we hadn't picked a captain.
それが団結できない要因か
Is that why we can't unite?
あんた含め船員は5人だ
Including you, the crew is five.
候補はこれで全員か
Are these candidates all of them?
3人不要、でいいか？
Three unneeded, is that fine?
武器をしまえ、海上だ
Put away weapons, we're at sea.
奪い合いなんて異常だ
Fighting over things is abnormal.
多数決が理想さ
Majority rule is ideal.
みんな自分に入れるか、そうか
Everyone votes for themselves, is that it?
というわけでサイレンス、きみ次第だ
Therefore, silence, it's up to you.
誰にしたって気にしないだ
Whoever it is, I don't care.
最後の航海だから行き先は選び放題さ
Since it's the final voyage, choose freely.
さあ舵を貸せ、代えだ
Now lend me the helm, let's swap.
プリーズ、ミスターサイレンス
Please, Mr. Silence,
ああ、どうしてどうして並べるのが
Ah, why, why is it so hard
きみにしかいないんだ
To find someone other than you?
お願い、choose me
Please, choose me.
ほら、早く、今日中に
Come on, quickly, today,
お願い、choose me, choose me
Please, choose me, choose me.
きみが今日選んでくれないとなにもできない
If you don't choose today, nothing can be done.
考えてくれないと心配に感じちゃうんだ
If you don't think about it, I get worried.
こんなところで迷ってると沈むよ、深海に
Hesitating here makes you sink to the deep sea.
沈むよ、深海に
Sinking into the deep sea.
濡れて気付いた、震える身体
Getting wet, I noticed my trembling body,
溢れてきちゃった、船底からだ
Pouring out from the ship's bottom.
穴が開いたんだ、座礁して
A hole opened up, running aground,
ああ、どうして直せるのがきみにしかいないんだ
Ah, why is there only you who can fix it?
お願い、修理
Please, repairs!
さあ、ほら今すぐに、塞いで熱して、熱して！
Come on, right now, seal it and get heated up!
きみが今日塞いでくれないとなにもできない
If you don't seal it today, nothing can be done.
閉じてる そろそろ限界値
Closing in, we're nearing our limit.
大事なもの 探しに行かない？
Shall we go search for what's precious?
偉大な夢の旅 新世界に
On a grand dream journey to a new world!
きみがいないと 意味なんてない
Without you, it has no meaning at all.
考えてくれないと 心配に
If you don't think about it with me,
感じちゃうんだ こんなところで
I start to get worried in a place like this.
迷ってると 行けないよ、絶対に
If you get lost here, we'll never make it!
行けないよ、絶対に
We'll never make it, absolutely not!
マリン出航!!
[Marine Set Sail!!]
世界が 壊れて行く
The world is falling apart.
泣き声が 聞こえていた
Crying voices could be heard.
汚れた拳 痛むほど 強く握った
I gripped my dirtied fists until they hurt.
当たり前に 笑ってた昨日は もうどこにもない
Yesterday's casual smiles are nowhere to be found.
明日がどんな日になるのか 誰も知らない
Nobody knows what kind of day tomorrow will bring.
正義にさえ 捨てられた今日
Today, even justice was abandoned.
取り戻すことを 誓う
I swear I'll take it back.
錨上げ！ 勇気の旗上げて
Weigh anchor! Raise the flag of courage!
旅立とう 嵐の海
Let's set sail into the stormy sea!
立ち上がれ 幸せは願えば
Stand up! If you wish for happiness,
手に入るほど 安くはない
it's not cheap enough to come easily.
守るために戦うなら どこまでなればいい
If I fight to protect, how far must I go?
幸せ簡単に 海の中消えてしまう
Happiness vanishes easily into the sea.
悲劇をただ見ていることが 許せないなら
If we can't forgive just watching the tragedy unfold,
ひとりきりで震えていたとは 一分消えはしない
The trembling solitude will never fade away.
それでも決意 胸にだけは もう迷わない
Still, with determination in my heart, I won't hesitate anymore.
道半ばで倒れた友に 託された言葉を抱き
Holding the words entrusted by friends who fell along the way,
錨上げ！ 自由の旗上げて
Weigh anchor! Raise the flag of freedom!
突き進め 荒れ狂う大海原
Charge ahead into the raging open sea!
燃え上がれ どんな雨だろうと
Blaze up, no matter what rain falls,
消えることなき 炎になれ
become an undying flame!
錨上げ！ 勇気の旗上げて
Weigh anchor! Raise the flag of courage!
旅立とう 嵐の海
Let's set sail into the stormy sea!
立ち上がれ 幸せは願えば
Stand up! If you wish for happiness,
手に入るほど 安くはない
it's not cheap enough to come easily.
守るために戦うなら どこまでなればいい
If I fight to protect, how far must I go?
ヨホホホ ホロヘイ
Yo-ho-ho-ho, horo-hey!
ホロヘイ ホロヘイ
Horo-hey, horo-hey!
ヨホホホ ホロヘイ
Yo-ho-ho-ho, horo-hey!
暁のシャバリの誰に立ち上がれ
Rise up to whosoever of the dawn's Shabari!
ヨホホホ ホロヘイ
Yo-ho-ho-ho, horo-hey!
ホロヘイ ホロヘイ
Horo-hey, horo-hey!
ぎりぎり いつか集まればやがて
Someday, if we gather at the very edge,
偉大なる大海原 錨上げ
across the great ocean, weigh anchor!
はい、ということで、まず2曲聴いていただきました！
So, first off, you've listened to two songs!
はい、本日は何の日？そう、宝鐘マリンお誕生日でーす！だーだーだ！
Yes, what day is it today? That's right, it's Houshou Marine's birthday! Ta-da-da!
はい、今日のハッシュタグは宝鐘マリン生誕祭2022。
Yes, today's hashtag is Houshou Marine Birthday 2022.
ま、なんですけど、ま、今日はね、何と言っても、ま、ここに書いてある通り、え、3Dのね、新衣装のお披露目もあります！
Well, anyway, today, whatever anyone says, as written right here, um, we're also revealing a brand new 3D outfit!
もうこれはね、隠して置くのは無理なんで、先に行っちゃいます。
I can't keep this hidden anymore, so I'll just say it right now.
でも、隠していることも一つあるんだよな。その隠していることも、え、終盤にね、お披露目したいと思うので、最後までしっかり見てください。どんな衣装だと思う？
However, there's also one thing I'm hiding. I want to reveal that towards the end, so please watch all the way through. What kind of outfit do you think it is?
超エッチです！毎回エッチです！
Super lewd! It's lewd every time!
てなわけで、なんかね、今日はね、メッセージを、なんかいただいている？というのを聴いているんですが、
That being said, it seems like, um, we've received some messages today? That's what I've been hearing, but...
なんか、おや? あ、
Wait, huh? Oh,
なんとね、あの、あの、あの、知ってますか君たち？あの、ほっこりモコモカちゃんからメッセージいただいてるみたいです。知ってるよね、きょうじ？知らないなんてことはないよね、モグラだよ、それは。
You know what? Um, do you guys know? It looks like we got a message from Hokkori Mocomoca-chan. You know her, Kyoji? There's no way you don't know, she's a mole.
いやね、すごく可愛いクマです。見れば分かる。ということで、じゃあメッセージお願いします！
Well, she's a super cute bear. You can tell just by looking. So, let's have the message!
こんにちはー！ほっこりモコモカだよ～
Hello~! I'm Hokkori Mocomoca~
きょうは、だいすきな、あ、ちょとまって、はや。マリンせんちょうのたんじょうび！
Today is my favorite—ah, wait, too fast—Marine-sencho's birthday!
わ～い！おめでとー！
Yay~! Happy birthday!
モカもおいわいにきたよ～！
Moca came to celebrate too~!
みてみて！モカがかざりつけをしたんだ～
Look, look! Moca did the decorations~
いちみのみんな～！いつもがんばっているマリンせんちょうに、ほっこりのまほう、モコモカパワーをいっしょにおくろう！
Everyone in Ichimi~! Let's send the magic of coziness, Mocomoca power, together to Marine-sencho who always works hard!
じゅんびはいいかな？
Are you ready?
せーのっ、モコモカパワー！
Ready, set, Mocomoca Power!
マリンせんちょうのもとにすてきなおくりものをしたよ。あの日モカと出会ってくれてありがとう。
I sent a wonderful gift to Marine-sencho. Thank you for meeting Moca that day.
これからもモカはマリンせんちょうのそばにいるよ～
Moca will stay by Marine-sencho's side from now on too~
まったね～！
See you later~!
可愛い！船長今初めて見たんですけど、可愛すぎる！ユーザーマジで可愛すぎ！
So cute! That's the first time sencho's ever seen that, but it's way too cute! Seriously too cute!
で、なんかね、おくりものが来ているっていうことなんですけど、ちょっと見てもいいですか？ちょっと、
And, um, it seems like a gift has arrived, can I take a look? Hold on,
え、待って、これ、きょうじゅん見える？見えないか？あ、今船長の元に、
Wait, can you see this, Kyojun? Can you see it? Ah, right now in sencho's hands,
わ、可愛い！あ、帽子かぶっちゃってるの！あ、ららら！可愛い！
Wah, cute! Ah, she's wearing a hat! Ah, ra-ra-ra! Cute!
ありがとう！ありがとうモカちゃん！可愛いモカちゃん！可愛い！
Thank you! Thank you, Moca-chan! Cute Moca-chan! Cute!
あ、キロスス！よしよしよしよし
Ah, AkiRosu! Yoshi yoshi yoshi yoshi
この曲選んでくれてさ。
You chose this song.
いや、船長の中では、アキロゼ先輩といえば、アリプロジェクトのイメージなんですよ。
Well, for you, sencho, AkiRosu-senpai gives off an ALI PROJECT image.
そうなんだ、嬉しいな。
Is that so? I'm happy.
逆に、逆にあり、アキロゼ先輩は、船長と歌うなら何がいいと思いますか？
Conversely, AkiRosu-senpai, what do you think would be good to sing with sencho?
マリンちゃんのさ、昭和歌謡の歌とかめちゃくちゃ好きだから、
I really like Marine-chan's Showa-era kayo songs,
あ、昭和系の歌を歌いたいんだよね。
Ah, you want to sing Showa-era songs.
あ、いいんじゃないですか？あの、キャンディーズとかどう？
Ah, isn't that good? Um, how about Candies?
「赤いリンゴくちびる　真っ白な白磁」
'Red apple lips, pure white porcelain'
めっちゃ好き！
I love it!
じゃあ次は絶対年下の男の子一緒に歌いましょうね！
Then next time let's definitely sing 'Toshishita no Otokonoko' together!
いいね！じゃあ次は年下の男の子で会おうしょ！じゃあね！
Sounds good! Let's meet with 'Toshishita no Otokonoko' next time! Bye-bye!
おめでとうね～！
Happy birthday~!
建前だけの感情論で
With emotion based solely on pretenses,
全てを図ろうなんて
trying to measure everything
そんなのはお門違い、
is completely missing the point,
笑わせないでよね
don't make me laugh.
だけどたまには楽しいことも必要だと思うの
But sometimes, I think fun things are necessary too,
気が済むまで私も満喫したいわ
and I want to fully enjoy myself until I'm satisfied.
あの日のお前が消えていった　心を指す嘘みたいに
That day, you disappeared, piercing my heart like a lie.
作りって混ざるような　この感じがたまらない
This mixed, fabricated feeling is irresistible.
ねえ、ぶっ飛んじゃうのが良いなら
Hey, if blowing our minds is good,
私をもっと大きくさせて
make me even bigger.
逃げるなんて許さないわ
I won't forgive you for running away.
やっぱりそんな態度なのかしら
I wonder if you're really going to take that attitude.
甘いのもいいと思うけれど 苦いのも嫌じゃない
I think sweet is fine too, but bitter isn't bad either.
そんな私の事を わがままだと言うの?
Do you call someone like me selfish?
馬鹿だとかアホだとか 言いたいだけ言えばいいわ
You can say I'm stupid or an idiot all you want.
他人の価値観なんて 私は知らないの
I don't care about other people's values.
菓子の皮から落ちていった
Falling from the pastry crust,
紫色の花みたいに
like a purple flower,
くるくると踊るようなこの感じがたまらない
this dizzy, dancing feeling is irresistible.
さぁどうなっちゃうのか見せてよ
Come on, show me what happens.
本能と理性がどちらが勝つのか
Whether instinct or reason will win.
超絶倫で魅せてよ
Show me with extreme vigor.
本当はここを欲しがるくせに
Even though you really want it here.
嬉しいとか 気持ちいいとか
Whether it feels good or happy,
小説それは自己満じゃん
novels, those are just self-satisfaction.
答えないって投げ捨てちゃっていいんじゃないって思わせて
Make me think it's fine to throw away and say 'I won't answer'.
もうぶっ飛ばんじゃったら良いでしょ
Once you've blown your mind, it's fine, right?
いったいどこに不満があるの
What on earth are you dissatisfied with?
いっそこうなったら逃がさない
Once it's come to this, I won't let you escape.
だからね ほらね 覚悟して
So hey, look, be prepared.
さぁどうなっちゃってもいいから
Come on, even if anything happens,
その目で最後まで見届けて
watch it through to the very end with those eyes.
どこまでいっても止まらない
No matter how far it goes, it won't stop.
だけどね でもね そろそろ限界に
But hey, you know, we're reaching the limit soon.
高嶺ルイに...あ、こよりは本当にぴったりだと思ったんですが
Takane Lui... ah, I thought it fit Koyori so perfectly,
ガチでぴったりだった！
but it really was a perfect match!
え、嬉しい、嬉しい！
Oh, I'm so happy, so happy!
いやでも、マリン先輩もめちゃくちゃセクシーで素晴らしかったです
But Marine-senpai, you were also super sexy and wonderful.
セクシーといえば船長、いやもう本当にエロ女主人としての立場が
Speaking of sexy, Captain—well, truly, your position as an erotic mistress...
あ、やばばれてんの? 高嶺ルイに今発見されてる
Ah, wait, is it being exposed? Takane Lui is discovering it now!
やだこれ！私セクシーだからな
No way! Because I'm sexy,
いや何これステキすぎすき
No, what is this, it's too wonderful!
これじゃマリンがロリータに見えちゃう
At this rate, Marine is going to look like a loli!
いや、マリン先輩も元々ロリですからね
Well, Marine-senpai is originally a loli, after all.
え？そんな...ロリばばあっていう感じで
Eh? Really... like a loli hag kind of vibe?
マリン、俺だけのババーになれよ
Marine, become my exclusive hag!
おばあちゃんになる...
I'm becoming a grandma...
レイちゃんメガドライブ買ってあげるからね メガドライブはちょっと古い
Rei-chan, I'll buy you a Sega Mega Drive... Mega Drive is a bit old!
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for an unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
holding close an unyielding wish,
海の色が紅く染まっていく
the color of the sea is dyed crimson.
無重力状態 このまま風にさらわれたい
In a weightlessness state, I want to be swept away by the wind just like this.
運命の色が赤く染まっていく
The color of destiny is dyed red,
無重力状態
in a weightlessness state.
このまま風にさらわれたい
I want to be swept away by the wind just like this.
いつも超えられないハードルを負けない気持ちでクリアしてきたけど
I've always cleared unjumpable hurdles with an undefeated spirit, but
出し切れない実力は誰のせい?
whose fault is it that I can't give it my all?
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for an unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
holding close an unyielding wish,
色褪せない心の地図を光にかざそう
let's hold up our unfading heart maps to the light.
どれだけ泣けば朝に出逢えるの
How much must I cry until I meet the morning?
孤独な夜 初めて限界を感じた日
On a lonely night, the day I first felt my limits.
どれだけ泣けば朝に出逢えるの
How much must I cry until I meet the morning?
孤独な夜 初めて限界を感じた日
On a lonely night, the day I first felt my limits.
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming at the unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
and embracing our unyielding wish,
海の色が紅く染まっていく 無重力状態
The sea turns crimson, a weightless state.
このままで風にさらわれたい
I want to be swept away by the wind just like this.
いつも跳べないハードルを
Always facing an unjumpable hurdle,
負けない気持ちでクリアしてきたけど
with an undefeatable spirit, we've cleared it, but
出し切れない実力は誰のせい?
whose fault is it that we can't unleash our true strength?
どれだけ泣けば 朝に出逢えるの
How much must I cry to meet the morning?
孤独な夜 初めて限界を感じた日
A lonely night, the day I first felt my limits.
きっと恋に落ちるのは まぶたみたいな
Surely, falling in love is like a fleeting
一瞬の情熱だけど
instantaneous passion, but
愛に続く坂道で 強さを覚えたい
on the path of love, I want to learn strength.
止まらない未来を夢見て
Dreaming of an unstoppable future,
口を閉ざし 瞳を輝かせてきたけれど
I closed my mouth and made my eyes shine, but
もっと大きな 優しさが 見えた
I could see a much greater kindness.
跳べないハードルを 負けない気持ちで クリアしてきたけど
Unjumpable hurdles, with an undefeated spirit, we cleared them, but
スタートラインに立つたびに 怯えていた
whenever we stood at the starting line, we were frightened.
止まらない未来を描いて 腕を伸ばし 心を開いて
Sketching an unstoppable future, reaching our arms out and opening our hearts,
止まらない未来を目指して ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
Aiming at the unstoppable future, embracing our unyielding wish,
色褪せない心の地図 光にかざそう
Let's hold up our unfading heart's map to the light.
はぁ～、というわけで! ホロライブの2人に 来てもらいました!
Haa~, and so! We had two Hololive members come join us!
ありがとうございましたー! よかったー
Thank you very much! Yay, I'm so glad!
そのホロライブっていうね、このほら、主人公的な2人を揃えて、バリバリのタイアップ曲を歌ってみたかったんですよ!
Having these two protagonist-like Hololive members together, I really wanted to sing an epic tie-up song with them!
よかった!
I'm so glad!
なんか、やっぱ2人に挟まれると、なんか、ちょっと完全敵? 敵なの? なんか敵じゃない?
Somehow, being sandwiched between the two of them... are they completely enemies? Are they enemies? Aren't they enemies?
敵だね! 敵だね!
They're enemies! They're enemies!
じゃああの2人と戦って! 戦って戦って戦って!
Then fight those two! Fight, fight, fight!
『ちょっとそこのお嬢さん 愛を語りませんか
"Hey you young lady over there, won't you talk about love?
月夜にめぐり逢えたこの縁(えにし)に
in this bond we chanced upon on a moonlit night,
流麗青美(りゅうれいそうび)の瞳 月光照らす銀の髪
eyes of fluid blue beauty, silver hair illuminated by moonlight,
今宵の誰よりも輝きております
you shine brighter than anyone tonight.
昨今な夜な夜る現る 夜霧の幻影の恐怖が
The terror of the nocturnal phantom appearing every night
もしも貴女を威(おび)やかすならば 偃越(えんえつ)ながら私
If it threatens you, allow me, presumptuously,
愛の語らい 序(ついい)でにと貴女の行先へお供致しましょう
to accompany you on your way while we speak of love.
鳴呼、嬉しいわ
Ah, how happy I am,
今宵のお相手は貴方?
Are you my partner for tonight?
ねえ、過ごしましょう
Hey, let's spend
蠢(うごめ)いて幻想的(ロマンティック)な夜を
a writhing, romantic night together.
出会いは唐突ながら
Although our encounter was abrupt,
月明りの下 惹かれ行く
drawn together beneath the moonlight.
月夜に飢える
Starving for the moonlit night,
昏(くら)い眼をした 狼の気配は
the presence of a wolf with dark eyes
押し付けがましい愛は
Imposing love
今宵も向かう先を探す
searches for its destination tonight as well.
その仮面の下に気付かれることも無いまま
Without anyone noticing beneath that mask...
今宵も 獲物を求め
Tonight too, in search of prey,
錆びつく夜更けに 外を歩くあなた
Walking outside in the rusting dead of night,
もそもそどちらへ お出ででしたか
Where on earth were you heading off to?
床の間の皿に 誰かの秘密を暴くのは
Exposing someone's secret on the alcove's dish,
あなたにあるまじき 行いでもなくて
Not that it's an act unbecoming of you,
月夜の綺麗な夜こそ 気をつけなければならないさ
On such a beautiful moonlit night, you must be careful.
ようなような現れる シリアルキラーに
Appearing out of nowhere like a serial killer—
月の照らす静寂に 騒ぎ立てるものこそ
Those who make a commotion in the moonlight's quiet,
肝心なくなれば 夜しのいではなくて
if they lose their nerve, won't even need the night's death—
鳴呼、イケナイよ 殺人鬼を駆り立てる言葉
Ah, it's no good, words that urge on the murderer.
彼を一体 何に駆り立てる言葉は
What on earth is driving him on?
ねえ、怯え会う者にこそ
Hey, to those who tremble in fear,
ものはにこそ 彼女は現れるさよ
she appears all the more—
出会いは 唐突ながら月明かり
An encounter, though sudden, under the moonlight,
のした光れ行く
drawn by the shining light,
月夜に飢える
famished in the moonlit night.
昏い眼をした
With dark, hollow eyes,
狼の気配は
the presence of a wolf
深まる 夜のしじまに切り滲む
deepens, bleeding into the silence of the night.
霧満ちる 街の灯の中で
Amidst the fog-filled city lights,
男と女は踊る
a man and a woman dance.
互いにねらいを定めて
Taking aim at each other,
今宵も 獲物はそこに
tonight too, the prey is right there.
一筋の 昏い独り言手に過ぎ
A single thread of a dark monologue passing through the hands,
月を背に 殺人鬼は 諦めを向いた
With the moon at her back, the murderer gave up and turned around.
出会いも 唐突ならば別れも
If encounters are sudden, so are partings—
刹那の出来事
events of a fleeting moment.
月夜に嗤う
Sneering at the moonlit night,
紅い眼をした
with crimson eyes,
狼の姿は
the wolf's figure
月を映す ナイフを手に
reflects the moon, holding a knife in hand,
佇む 殺人鬼
a lingering serial killer.
決して満たされることはなくやがては
Never to be satisfied, before long,
再び彷徨う
she wanders once again.
今宵も 獲物はは何処に
Tonight too, where is the prey?
「よっし、坂本に勝った！」
"All right, I beat Sakamata!"
「え？待って、勝ってないじゃん！」
"Eh? Wait, you didn't win!"
「いや、船長ね、坂本を殺すのが夢だったんだ！」
"Well, Captain's dream was to kill Sakamata!"
「ひどい、掃除屋なのに！」
"How awful, and I'm a cleaner!"
「掃除しました！」
"I cleaned you up!"
「いやね、この曲は東方のボーカルアレンジの曲なんだけど…歌詞が坂本にぴったりなの！」
"Actually, this song is a Touhou vocal arrangement... and the lyrics fit Sakamata so perfectly!"
「めちゃくちゃ金髪とかさ、シリアルキラーとかさ、だから坂本が勝つと思ったのに！」
"With the blonde hair and being a serial killer and all, I thought Sakamata would win!"
「いやちょっと勝ってみた。でもめちゃくちゃ良かったです！」
"Well, I tried winning a bit. But it was super good!"
「いやもう次こそ絶対マリン氏が勝つからね！」
"Next time, Marine-shou will definitely win for sure!"
「船長の赤髪がかち…勝ち！船長のく…」
"Captain's red hair wi... win! Captain's..."
「坂本の勝ちー！」
"Sakamata's win!"
1000%SPARKING! 作詞：こだまさおり、佐藤こづえ 作曲：大久保薫
[Song: 1000%SPARKING! / Lyrics: Saori Kodama, Kozue Sato / Music: Kaoru Okubo]
胸のピストル鳴らして やけに鼓動がジャマする
My chest's pistol rings out, my heart beating too wildly in the way.
落ち着いていられない そんな事情
I can't stay calm, that's just how it is.
胸のピストル鳴らして
Ring the pistol in my chest,
やけに動悸がジャマをする
My heartbeat is getting in the way so much.
落ち着いていられない
I can't stay calm,
そんな事情
such are the circumstances.
譲れないその想いに
To that unyielding feeling,
キミが輝くから
because you shine so brightly,
くじけそうな今日も平気
even a discouraging day is fine,
成功の5秒前
5 seconds before success!
もっと Sparking Now!
More, Sparking Now!
強くタフなハート
With a strong, tough heart,
磨いたら世界は見違える
If you polish it, the world will look different!
もっと Sparking Now! 強くタフなハート
More, Sparking Now! A strong and tough heart!
磨いたら世界は見違える
If you polish it, the world will look completely different!
Sparking Now! 高くかざしたソウル
Sparking Now! A soul held high!
力の限り 目指せ1000%
To the limit of your power, aim for 1000%!
もっとずっと遠い場所だと思っていた 手の届かない夢物語
I always thought it was a much more distant place, an unreachable dream story...
「待って、ねえ待って!お父さんでしょ!?」
("Wait, hey wait! You're my father?!")
どんな小さな光も見逃さずにいた
Without overlooking even the smallest light,
少しでもあなたに近づくために
in order to get just a little closer to you,
「この命、たとえ失ってもお守りします!」
("I will protect you, even if I lose this life!")
闇を切り裂く胸の奥の勇気 迷いを断ち切る白い翼
The courage deep in my chest tearing through the darkness, white wings cutting through hesitation...
「もう、一人で何でも出来るって思うんじゃないわよ!」
("Don't think you can do everything by yourself anymore!")
立ち止まりそうになっても今ここにある笑顔 胸に閉じ込めて
Even if I feel like stopping, I lock the smile here and now deep in my heart—
「守られてばかりは嫌やねん!ウチも守りたい!」
("I hate only being protected! I want to protect you too!")
だから Burning Heart! 熱く燃やすよ今
So, Burning Heart! Burn passionately right now,
手探りの世界を突き抜けて
breaking through this fumbling world!
Burning Heart! 闇を照らしたのは
Burning Heart! What illuminated the darkness
自分自身の光る1000%
was your own shining 1000%!
もっと Sparking Now! 強くタフなハート
More, Sparking Now! A strong and tough heart!
磨いたら世界は見違える
If you polish it, the world will look completely different!
Sparking Now! 高くかざしたソウル
Sparking Now! A soul held high!
力の限り 目指せ1000%
To the limit of your power, aim for 1000%!
Burning Heart! 熱く燃やすよ今
Burning Heart! Burn passionately right now,
手探りの世界を突き抜けて
breaking through this fumbling world!
Burning Heart! 闇を照らしたのは
Burning Heart! What illuminated the darkness
自分自身の光る1000%
was your own shining 1000%!
あ、スイちゃん！あ、スイちゃん！初めて一緒に歌ったじゃん！
Ah, Suichan! Ah, Suichan! We sang together for the first time!
初めて！いや今までね、こう混ざり合っての
For the first time! Well, up until now, mixing like this—
一緒終わってさ、1000%SPARKING!は初めてで
finishing together, doing "1000%SPARKING!" for the first time...
え、どう？なんか結構バランス良くないこれさ？
Eh, how is it? Doesn't the balance look pretty good here?
なんかバ、バランス、色のバランスの話ね？
Like, ba— balance, you mean the color balance?
なんかほら赤だからほらなんかチンチクリンだの
Like, see, since I'm red, I look like a shorty or something—
なんかスイちゃんの隣にたつとなんか
When I stand next to Suichan, somehow...
なんか、なんだろう、あの、ピクミンみたいだよね？
Somehow, what is it, um, we look like Pikmin, right?
ピク、え、キャプテン・オリマーの方？赤ピクミンのほう？
Pik— eh, Captain Olimar? Red Pikmin?
赤ピクミンのキャプテン・オリマーね！違う違う違う！
Red Pikmin's Captain Olimar! No, no, no, no!
いや、スイちゃん、やめてやめてやめて！そんな話でピクミン使わないで！
No, Suichan, stop it, stop it! Don't use Pikmin for that kind of talk!
赤ピクミンしか無い！
Only Red Pikmin!
今日ね、スイちゃんが選んでくれたこの曲、あ、1000%SPARKING!懐かしいの歌いたいのに
Today, Suichan chose this song, ah, "1000%SPARKING!", she wanted to sing something nostalgic—
知ってた？懐かしの曲、知ってたよ。一緒いに歌いたいって本当に言ってくれて。
Did you know? A nostalgic song, I knew it. She really said she wanted to sing it together.
ありがとう。なんかすごい高かったよね、できばえ。
Thank you. It turned out amazingly high quality, didn't it?
本当に、めちゃくちゃ高かったでしょ？そう、スイちゃん踊りも本当に完璧で。
Really, wasn't it super high quality? Yeah, Suichan's dancing was truly perfect too.
スイちゃん踊りも踊りもマスターも本当に完璧。お疲れ様！
Suichan, your dancing and mastery were truly perfect. Good job!
お疲れ様！
Good job!
Dan-dan こころ Dan-dan アツク
Beat by beat, my heart heats up,
夢いっぱい叶えてみせる
I'll make my dreams come true!
Dan-dan ススム Dan-dan ハジケル
Step by step, we advance, bursting with energy,
未来をしっかり見て！
Keep your eyes firmly on the future!
(Hi hi, ススメ! まだまだLet's go!! Hi hi, ススメ! ほらほらLet's go!!)
(Hi hi, let's go! Still going, let's go!! Hi hi, let's go! Look, look, let's go!!)
大事なことはなんだっけ?
What was that important thing again?
ちいさな努力が明日を作るんだ
Small efforts build tomorrow.
いまを愛してぶつかりおう!
Love the present and collide with it!
もっと近くで語りあいたいな
I want to talk more closely with you,
艶やかな君とどこまで走ろうか
How far shall I run with radiant you?
(果てまで)走ればいいさ (限界しらない All right?)
(To the very end) Just run on (No limits, all right?)
これからの Wonderful Rush
Our Wonderful Rush from here on,
みんな幸せになるため
So everyone can find happiness,
新しい世界 探しに行こうよ
Let's go search for a brand new world!
迷ったら Wonderful Rush
If you get lost, it's a Wonderful Rush,
僕は輝きを信じて
Believing in our radiance,
遥か遠くの虹だけど...そう、きっとつかんで!(Hi!!)
A rainbow far, far away... Yes, we'll surely grasp it! (Hi!!)
Dan-dan こころ Dan-dan アツク
Beat by beat, my heart heats up,
夢いっぱい叶えてみせる
I'll make my dreams come true!
Dan-dan ススム Dan-dan ハジケル
Step by step, we advance, bursting with energy,
未来をつかまえて!
Seize the future!
(Hi hi, ススメ! まだまだLet's go!! Hi hi, ススメよ!)
(Hi hi, let's go! Still going, let's go!! Hi hi, let's go on!)
人生気分で上下左右
Life's moods go up, down, left, and right,
運命ときに急展開
Destiny sometimes shifts in a flash.
最低↓ 最高↑ 最大↑ 最新↑
Lowest ↓ Highest ↑ Maximum ↑ Latest ↑
Let's go! 遠く に Super jump!!
Let's go! A far away Super jump!!
なんだろうね不思議だよ
I wonder why, it's so mysterious,
楽しいと感じるこの時は
Whenever I feel this joy,
瞬間のようで永遠のようでね
It feels like a moment, yet like eternity.
一緒に跳ぼう Dan-da-Dan-Dan!
Let's jump together, Dan-da-Dan-Dan!
大事だよ (なんだっけ?) ちいさな努力 (そうだった!)
It's important (What was it?) Small efforts (That's right!)
いまが好きで (愛なんだ?) ぶつかるんだ (そうなんだ!)
Loving the present (Is that love?) We collide (That's right!)
勢いよくね (大胆に?) 一生懸命 (そうだった!)
With great force (Boldly?) With all our might (That's right!)
勢いづけて (大胆に?) 一生懸命だ!
Momentum driving us (Boldly?) With all our might!
もっと気持ちを分かちあいたくて
Wanting to share our feelings even more,
隣にいる君いつでもいっしょに
You by my side, always together,
(いるから) いっしょがいいね (心配いらない All right?)
(Because you're here) Together is best (No need to worry, all right?)
はじまりの Wonderful stage
The beginning of a Wonderful stage,
みんな次の場所 立つんだ
Everyone stands in the next place.
めぐり逢う季節 新鮮な景色
Seasons we cross paths in, fresh scenery,
胸はずむ Wonderful stage
Our hearts race on this Wonderful stage.
僕が目指すのはきれいな 遥か遠くの虹だから… さあ、出発だよ!
What I aim for is a beautiful rainbow far, far away... Now, let's set off!
Wonderful... Wao! どうしようか? Dreams come true
Wonderful... Wao! What should we do? Dreams come true
当然 Let's go! Three, two, one, zero!!
Of course, Let's go! Three, two, one, zero!!
Hi hi, Super jump! Oh yeah, Super jump!!
Life is wonder まだまだ Let's go!!
Life is wonder, still more, Let's go!!
Hi hi, Super jump! Oh yeah, Super jump!!
Life is wonder Wonderful rush
もっと近くで語りあいたいな
I want to talk more closely with you,
艶やかな君とどこまで走ろうか
How far shall I run with radiant you?
(果てまで)走ればいいさ (限界そんなに? No thank you, ok!)
(To the very end) Just run on (Such limits? No thank you, ok!)
Oh yeah (心配いらない All right!!)
Oh yeah (No need to worry, all right!!)
これからの Wonderful Rush
Our Wonderful Rush from here on,
みんな幸せになるため
So everyone can find happiness,
新しい世界 探しに行こうよ
Let's go search for a brand new world!
迷ったら Wonderful Rush
If you get lost, it's a Wonderful Rush,
僕は輝きを信じて 遥か遠くの虹だけど いつか手にする
Believing in our radiance, a rainbow far, far away, we'll someday grasp in our hands.
Wonderful stage
みんな次の場所 立つんだ
Everyone stands in the next place.
めぐり逢う季節 新鮮な景色
Seasons we cross paths in, fresh scenery,
胸はずむ Wonderful stage
Our hearts race on this Wonderful stage.
僕が目指すのはきれいな 遥か遠くの虹だから… さあ、出発だよ!
What I aim for is a beautiful rainbow far, far away... Now, let's set off!
Dan-dan こころ Dan-dan アツク
Beat by beat, my heart heats up,
夢いっぱい叶えてみせる
I'll make my dreams come true!
Dan-dan ススム Dan-dan ハジケル
Step by step, we advance, bursting with energy,
未来をしっかり見て!
Keep your eyes firmly on the future!
Dan-dan こころ Dan-dan アツク
Beat by beat, my heart heats up,
夢いっぱい叶えてみせる
I'll make my dreams come true!
Dan-dan ススム Dan-dan ハジケル
Step by step, we advance, bursting with energy,
未来をしっかり見て!
Keep your eyes firmly on the future!
Dan-dan こころ Dan-dan アツク
Beat by beat, my heart heats up,
夢いっぱい叶えてみせる
I'll make my dreams come true!
Dan-dan ススム Dan-dan ハジケル
Step by step, we advance, bursting with energy,
未来をしっかり見て!
Keep your eyes firmly on the future!
(Hi hi, ススメ! まだまだLet's go!! Hi hi, ススメ! ほらほらLet's go!!)
(Hi hi, let's go! Still going, let's go!! Hi hi, let's go! Look, look, let's go!!)
大事なことはなんだっけ?
What was that important thing again?
ちいさな努力が明日を作るんだ
Small efforts build tomorrow.
いまを愛してぶつかりおう!
Love the present and collide with it!
あれ？え？
Huh? Eh?
え、でもちょっと待って。
Wait, hold on a second.
あれ？本物のマリンはいない？
Huh? Is the real Marine not here?
え、そうだよ！
Yeah, exactly!
あれ？マリンどこ？え？いなくね？
Huh? Where's Marine? Eh? Isn't she gone?
あれ？じゃあ誰？
Huh? Then who is this?
じゃじゃーん！なんだ！
Ta-da! What is this?!
なんかセクシーなお姉さん来たんだけど。
It's like some sexy older sister just appeared.
え、そうなんです。誕生日ということで、
That's right. Since it's my birthday,
何歳になったと思う？
how old do you think I turned?
そう、17歳さ、4、4周目。
That's right, 17 years old... fourth lap.
そう、17歳4周目って、17×4ってこと？
Wait, 17 years old on the 4th lap means 17 times 4?
えっ、そういうこと？
Eh, is that what it means?
いや、だから今回の衣装はちゃんとね、成長したマリンということで、ちょっと年をとってみました。勇気をだして勇気の決断、年をとるという決断をしましたけど、
Yeah, so for this outfit, as a properly grown-up Marine, I tried aging a bit. I mustered up the courage to make the resolute decision to age,
けどめちゃめちゃエロくね？服。
but isn't this outfit super lewd?!
大丈夫、大丈夫！
It's fine, it's fine!
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
はい、こちらの衣装ね、100万人記念でいただきました。
Yes, I received this outfit to commemorate 1 million subscribers.
じゃじゃ、じゃじゃーん！
Ta-ta-ta-da!
え？おっぱいがすごい！
Eh? Her boobs are huge!
え、やばくない？
Eh, isn't that crazy?
え、何が何が？
Eh, what, what?
え、なんのこと？めちゃめちゃ
Eh, what are you talking about? Super...
いやでもさ、目の前に来たから抱きしめてほしいのかと思って。
Well, but, since she came right in front of me, I thought she wanted a hug.
え、やめて！やめて！目の前に来たから抱きしめてほしいのかと思って。
Eh, stop it! Stop it! I thought you wanted a hug since you came right in front of me.
え、テーマとかあるんですか？テーマ。
Eh, is there a theme or anything? A theme.
テーマね。毎回毎回あーさーあいせーいせんちょーのお母さんですね。毎回毎回エッチな感じでおねがいしますと言って、丸投げしてるんですけど、そしたらこうなりました。
The theme. Every time, it's like "Captain's mother-in-law style, please make it lewd every time," and I just leave it to them, and this is how it turned out.
えー、でもめっちゃ可愛い！
Eh, but it's super cute!
いいね、いいよね！
Nice, very nice!
え、なんか、え、
Eh, like, eh,
髪の毛も可愛いね。
her hair is cute too.
あ、そうなの。髪の毛も、ほら！ほら、こんなに！
Ah, that's right. The hair too, look! Look, it's so long!
えー、めちゃめちゃ長くなってるね！
Eh, it got super long!
めちゃめちゃ可愛い！
Super cute!
え、みんなもしさ、これ、脱いでほしい？
Eh, do you guys want me to take this off?
いや、大丈夫だよ。
No, it's fine.
なんかそろそろ帰ろ、帰ろう
Like, we should head home soon, head home
そうそう、時間も、時間だから。バイバイ！脱いでほしい？
Yeah, yeah, because of time. Bye-bye! Do you want her to take it off?
脱いだところみ、あれ、みんな。脱いだところ見たい？誰も、あれ、
The part where she's undressed... wait, everyone. Do you want to see her undressed? Nobody... wait...
海賊ならヨーホー！ お宝かき集めヨーホーさ！
If you're pirates, Yo-ho! Gather up the treasure, Yo-ho!
今こそもとめ！ 宝箱解読だ！
Now is the time to seek it! Crack open the treasure chest!
Ahoy!! 我ら宝鐘海賊団☆
Ahoy!! We are the Houshou Pirates☆
踊るAhoy!! 見るAhoy!! (Ahoy! Ahoy!)
Dancing Ahoy!! Watching Ahoy!! (Ahoy! Ahoy!)
全速前進だ！ ズッ友！
Full speed ahead! Best friends for life!
ズッ友！ だよはサンサンと輝く日よりだ！
Best friends for life! The sun shines brightly today!
最高！ 最高のテンション 奈落の底のセドムラコを海で！
The best! The highest tension, sinking into the abyss of the sea!
さあ るすばし お金 兄貴がHappy おねだりはドグラマク
Come on, watch out for money, older brother is Happy, begging is Dogramaku
キラキラ 夜をふっ飛ばそう マイハウスで夢を見て
Sparkling, blowing away the night, dreaming in my house
ああ 神様 いつかこのマリンを本物の海賊にして下さい！
Ah, God, please someday make this Marine a real pirate!
声を出して さあ 出発だ 我ら宝鐘海賊団！
Raise your voices, come on, let's set sail, we are the Houshou Pirates!
コンパス片手に旗を掲げ この海をジャックしちゃおう
Compass in hand, raise the flag, let's jack this ocean!
夜空撃って おいでよ 共にヨーホー ヨーホー 叫ぼう
Shoot at the night sky, come along, let's shout Yo-ho, Yo-ho together!
ああ 最高の日びよ こここそ我が船へ
Ah, the greatest days, this place is truly my ship!
踊るAhoy!! 見るAhoy!! (Ahoy! Ahoy!)
Dancing Ahoy!! Watching Ahoy!! (Ahoy! Ahoy!)
1 2 サバサバ！
1, 2, refreshing!
熱く 語ろうよパッション 想いを解き放て！
Passionately let's talk about passion, unleash your feelings!
遊ぶとき煌めくファッション 形から入るタイプです 発進 準備の前 走れ 菓子こい列車 憂鬱も蹴れるわ
Playing while sparkling fashion, type that enters from appearance, before launching preparation, run, confectionery train, can kick away melancholy too
キラキラ しみじみ汗の滴るイブモ
Sparkling, deeply sweating drops of Eve-mo
だ けど 神様 女子高生だと 晩されちゃうのですね
But God, if I'm a high school girl, I'll end up banned, right?
はなっ から 奪われたら取り戻せ それが宝鐘海賊団！
From the start, if it's stolen, take it back, that's the Houshou Pirates!
君達とならかぞえきれない 伝説のエルドラド
With you guys, countless legendary El Dorados
夜空 楽しめや 歌おうよ 二人じゃない ああ この景色
Enjoy the night sky, let's sing, not just two of us, ah, this scenery!
最高な仲間よ 歌が下手だ歌えや 騒げや騒げ
The greatest comrades, sing if you're bad at singing, make noise, make noise!
踊るAhoy!! 見るAhoy!! (Ahoy! Ahoy!) おなじ野良野良のオマタってそう
Dancing Ahoy!! Watching Ahoy!! (Ahoy! Ahoy!) Same stray-stray crotch is like that
サッカー 片手に生き残りますよ
Soccer in one hand, surviving!
宝鐘海賊団 世界で一番 かわいいよー！
Houshou Pirates, the cutest in the world!
Ahoy!! 我ら宝鐘海賊団☆
Ahoy!! We are the Houshou Pirates☆
秘宝は 秘宝は エロガキチ
The treasure is, the treasure's a perverted brat!
秘宝は 秘宝は ばっきゅん ばっきゅん
The treasure is, bang-bang!
おジョーさん パンツを見ろ パンチラのゲリラ
Young lady, check out those panties, panty-flash guerrilla!
お宝 お宝 お宝 お宝
Treasure, treasure, treasure, treasure!
戻し 戻し 戻し 戻し
Put it back, put it back!
脳内マキシマム 脳内マキシマム
Brain maximum, brain maximum!
船長の絶対言うこと 聞いてみたい？
Do you want to obey the Captain's every command?
もっと もっと うんふ うんふ もっと もっと
More, more, mhm mhm, more, more!
セクシービーム もっと もっと
Sexy beam, more, more!
いやーん バイキング もっと もっと
Nooo, viking, more, more!
タッチしな もっと もっと もっと もっと
Touch me, more, more, more, more!
セビ セビ セビ もっと もっと もっと
Sevi sevi sevi, more, more, more!
前はぎょっと もっと もっと もっと
In front, it's startling, more, more!
出逢って5秒で 絶賛発情中！
Five seconds after meeting, in full estrus!
はぁ、船長は君たちをそんな子に育てた覚えはありません！本当にね、ねぇ、だぞ？
Haah, the Captain doesn't remember raising you kids like that! Really, right?
立てば地獄、座れば地獄、歩く姿は、ペテン？
Standing is hell, sitting is hell, walking style is... a swindler?
夢を見ろよ こんな船で
Dream on board this ship!
後悔なんてさせない！君たちのおかげで私は船長になれるから！
I won't let you regret it! Thanks to you all, I can be a captain!
絶賛発情中！
In full estrus!
声を上げて さあ出発だ 我ら海賊団 海賊団
Raise your voices, now set sail, we are the pirate crew!
コンパス片手に日はを上げ この海をジャックしちゃおう
Compass in hand, raise the flag, let's jack this ocean!
夜空たどって おいでおいで ともひよー
Following the night sky, come here!
よーほーよーほー さけべ ああ 最高の痺れ
Yo-ho, yo-ho, shout out, ah, the ultimate thrill!
ようこそ我が船へ パワフルシャワーの 海賊だ
Welcome aboard my ship, the pirate crew of powerful showers!
コンパス片手に日はを上げ この海をジャックしちゃおう
Compass in hand, raise the flag, let's jack this ocean!
それではいきますよ 出発！
Here we go now, set sail!
宝鐘マリン オリジナル楽曲第四弾
[Title: Houshou Marine 4th Original Song]
I'm Your Treasure Box *あなたはマリンせんちょうをたからばこからみつけた。
[Title: I'm Your Treasure Box]
魅惑を隠す箱 秘宝に香る危なげ
A box hiding allure, fragrant treasure looking dangerous,
な dangerous marine smell ♡ahoy♡
a dangerous marine smell ♡ahoy♡
dangerous marine smell
(これ開けたら君たちになんと言ってあげておくべきかな…？)
(What should I say to you guys when you open this...?)
「探してたのはせ・ん・ちょ・お？」
("Were you searching for the Ca-pt-ain?")
うーん…「あぁん♡そんなにがっついちゃダメだぞ♡」かな？
Hmm... "Aah♡ Don't get so greedy, okay♡"? Or maybe...
「お宝より魅力的な”モノ”見つけちゃった…？」 いいじゃない♡
("Did you find something more attractive than treasure...?") Isn't it nice♡
誘うガーネットの赤 極上の海賊の秘宝
The inviting red of garnet, the ultimate pirate's treasure,
それは私 艶が溢れ漂う香りを
that is me. An aura overflowing with allure,
どうか怖がらないで 開けてみて
please don't be scared, try opening it
sexy世界一 superピチピチっ ぶっちぎり船長捕まえたい?
Sexy number one, super perky, wanna catch the runaway captain?
you're gonna get the treasure maybe tasting me 私の甘さが欲しいでしょ
You're gonna get the treasure maybe tasting me, you want my sweetness, right?
(ah-hoy!!da-ba-da-boi)
(ah-hoy!! da-ba-da-boi)
秘宝の鍵を優しく刺して 宝庫の扉マジで早く開けて
Gently insert the key to the treasure, open the vault's door really fast
じれったい貴方の手 海図にこぼす甘いため息 tease
Your impatient hands, a sweet sigh spilled on the map, tease
純紅のバラがしおれる前に we will sail the seven seas
Before the crimson rose withers, we will sail the seven seas
summer sun smiling with glee 股にかけ進め
Summer sun smiling with glee, striding forward,
shining ocean of marine 股ってワードからなに想像してんの
shining ocean of marine, what are you imagining from that word?
now please grant my dearest dream open up this box open it right now or i will scream
(あーーーーーーーーーーーーーーっ！)
(Aaaaaaaaaaaaaah!)
泣く子も黙る naughty 悩殺ビーム キミたちももう我慢できなくなっちまった？
Naughty killer beam that even crying children quiet down, you guys can't hold back anymore?
you're gonna own the pleasure maybe love of me 私の全てを手に入れて ahhh
You're gonna own the pleasure maybe love of me, get all of me, ahhh
(ah-hoy!!da-ba-da-boi)
(ah-hoy!! da-ba-da-boi)
金銀財宝 はたした金でしょ しわしわになっちゃう
Gold, silver, and treasures, or is it money? Wrinkled up,
誰か助けて マジで遠征しすぎ キミたち何考えてるの
someone help, you guys went way too far on the expedition, what are you thinking?
分かってるんだぞ ワッ！ 欲望だから今すぐ開けてよ 宝箱 キミを待つガーネット…
I know it, wa! It's desire, so open the treasure box right now, garnet waiting for you...
魅惑を隠す箱
A box hiding allure,
秘宝に香る危険な
emitting a dangerous scent.
dangerous marine smell
これ開けたら君たちになんて言ってあげるべきかな…？
If I open this, what should I say to you guys...?
「探してたのは せ・ん・ち・ょ・お？」
"Are you looking for Se・n・chou?"
うーん…「あん❤そんなにがっついちゃダメだぞ❤」
Hmm... "Ah❤ Don't get so greedy❤"
かな？「お宝より魅力的な“モノ”見つけちゃった…？」いいじゃない❤
"Did you find something more attractive than treasure...?" Goodness❤
誘うガネットの赤 最高の海賊の秘宝
The alluring garnet red, the ultimate pirate treasure,
それは私
that is me.
艶が溢れ漂う 香りをどうぞ怪しまないで 開けてみて
Overflowing with allure, please don't be suspicious of the scent, try opening it.
(アッハッハッハ…❤)
(Ahahahaha...❤)
sexy世界一 superピチピチ
The sexiest in the world, super fresh and lively,
ぶっちぎり船長捕まえたいかない？
want to catch runaway Captain?
you’re gonna get the treasure
you're gonna get the treasure
maybe tasting me
私の甘さが欲しいでしょ
You want my sweetness, don't you?
(ah-hoy!!da-ba-da-boi)
(ah-hoy!! da-ba-da-boi)
秘宝の鍵を優しく挿して
Gently insert the key to the secret treasure,
宝庫の扉マジで早く開けて
open the vault door seriously fast!
(❤ ahoy ❤)
じれったい貴方の手 海図にこぼす甘いため息のtease
Your impatient hands, a sweet sigh spilling onto the map... tease
(yeah…)
(yeah...)
純紅のバラがしおれる前に
Before the crimson rose withers,
we will sail the seven seas
(七つの大海を)
(we will sail the seven seas)
summer sun smiling with glee
(股にかけ進め)
(moving forward across the world)
shining ocean of marine
(股ってワールドからなに想像してんの)
(What are you imagining with that word?)
now please grant my dearest dream
open up this box
open it right now or i will scream
(さもないと)
(otherwise)
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaa ! ! ! ! ! ! !
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa ! ! ! ! ! ! !
(あーぽろぽろぽろお…)
(Ah, poro-poro-poro-o...)
泣く子も黙る naughty 悩殺ビーム
Naughty captivating beam that silences crying children,
キミたちももう我慢できなくなる？
can you guys not hold back anymore either?
you’re gonna own the pleasure
you're gonna own the pleasure
maybe love of me ?
私の全てを手に入れて
Take everything of mine into your hands
(❤❤❤ ahhh ❤❤❤)
(ah-hoy!!da-ba-da-boi)
(ah-hoy!! da-ba-da-boi)
金銀財宝はした金でしょ
Gold and silver treasures are mere pocket change, right?
しわしわになっちゃう 誰か助けて
I'll become all wrinkled, someone help me!
マジで遠慮しすぎ キミたち何考えてんの
Seriously being too polite, what are you guys thinking?
分かっているんだわ 渇望だから今すぐ開けてよ
I know it's a craving, so open it right now!
宝箱
Treasure box
(open up this box)
貴方を押すガネット…
Garnet pushing you...
(キミ…キミたち…開けて～！！)
(You... you guys... open it up~~!!)
はーい、みんなたちいかがでしたでしょうかー！お誕生日お祝いしてくれてサンキュー！
Hi everyone, how was it?! Thank you for celebrating my birthday!
今日ひらめきました、「I'm Your Treasure Box」あなたはいきなり宝箱から見つけたミュージックビデオこのあと22時からプレミア公開です！
Today I came up with it, the MV for "I'm Your Treasure Box" premieres right after at 22:00!
24時から各種音楽サイトにて配信開始ですよ！ミュージックビデオも曲もエッチになってます！
Distribution on various music sites starts at 24:00! Both the MV and the song are quite lewd!
さあそして今年もグッズ出させていただきますよ！
And now, we're releasing merchandise this year too!
あー買えよかったと思えないようここは思い切ってぜひともごこうにゅうください！
So you don't think "ah I should've bought it", please make up your minds and definitely purchase them!
まずはこちら、B2タペストリーです！今回の新衣装で船長の母あかさあい先生描き下ろしです！
First is this, the B2 tapestry! Illustrated by Captain's "mother" Akasa Ai-sensei in the new outfit!
年年とろんじょさまぜんとしていくマリンのじょーみタップリなイラストになっています！
It's an illustration full of Marine's womanly charm becoming more and more mature each year!
これでいつでも見下されて気持ちよくなれる！
With this you can be looked down on anytime and feel good!
続いてこちら、一味Tシャツです！マリンとおそろいパーカーは夏場はやっぱり暑いのでこの海賊風としたボーダーシャツでいこう！
Next is this, the Ichimi T-shirt! Matching hoodies with Marine are too hot in summer, so let's go with this pirate-style border shirt!
船長のシンボルマークも入っていて、普通のボーダーシャツとはわけが違う。
It has the Captain's symbol mark too, making it different from ordinary border shirts.
外で着るのが恥ずかしい？そんな時は家でウォーリーを探せっこするすることも可能です！
Embarrassed to wear it outside? In that case, you can also play "Where's Wally?" at home!
そしてこちらは船長が描きました！ラバーストラップです！不人気な絵柄があるとショックするのでランダムにしました！何が出ても必ず喜んでください！
And this is drawn by the Captain! A rubber strap! If there's an unpopular design I'd be shocked, so I made it random! No matter what you get, please definitely be happy!
そしてそしてこちら航海日誌風手帳！大人の男が使ってもイケてるし、メスも優勝確実のおしゃれ手帳！船長の帽子のキーホルダーみたいなのもついてます！
And this, the voyage logbook-style notebook! Stylish enough for adult men to use, and a sure-win stylish notebook for women too! It even comes with a miniature of the Captain's hat keychain!
はい、そして今回もフルセットございます！すべてまとめてご購入いただけましたらば数量限定直筆メッセージ入りポストカードそう
Yes, and we have a full set this time too! If you purchase everything together, you get the quantity-limited handwritten message postcard and...
生誕祭前日をイメージしたマリンと君のラブラブシチュエーションボイスをプレゼントします！
...we present a lovey-dovey situation voice of Marine and you imagining the day before her birthday!
数量限定が売り切れましたらば、複製メッセージ＆サイン入りポストカードになります！こちらもね船長がぎっしりと想いを込めてメッセージ書いたので、まあこれはこれで嬉しいみたいなとこがある。
If the quantity-limited one sells out, it will be a reproduced message & signed postcard! The Captain wrote a message packed with feelings here too, so this has its own kind of happiness.
ということで宝鐘マリン誕生日記念グッズ2022、22時から販売開始です！Twitterや概要欄のURLはチェックお願いします！
With that, Houshou Marine's Birthday Commemoration Goods 2022 go on sale starting at 22:00! Please check Twitter and the URL in the description!
あ、それから船長のフィグマも7月29日から受注開始していますのでぜひともゲットしてくださいね！
Oh, and Captain's figma is also open for orders starting July 29th, so be sure to get it!
そして何やらホロライブ夏場から告知が少しだけあるようです！今からお知らせいたしますよ！
And it seems there are a few announcements from Hololive Summer! I'll let you know now!
私が…
I...
やらなくちゃ…
I have to do it...
キミたち、今の見ましたかー！？
Everyone, did you just see that?!
ということで、なんと！ホロライブサマー2022
And with that, amazingly,
本日より開催しまーす！
Hololive Summer 2022 starts today!
わあ、ポチポチポチポチ… いやサマーといえば船長。
Yay, click click click click... Well, summer means the Captain.
もう2年近く…2年か？
For almost two years... two years?
2年くらい本当にね、脱ぎたいという思いでやってきたんですけども
For about two years, I really wanted to strip...
ああ、これより脱げるのかな。いやでもね、キミたち落ち着いて。
Ah, can I strip even more? But hey everyone, calm down.
脱ぐのが全てじゃない。サマーって色々あるから。
Stripping isn't everything. Summer has all sorts of things.
え？まあ、キミたちどうせ水着だと思ってるんでしょうけど。
Eh? Well, you guys probably think it's just swimwear anyway.
わかんないからね！まだわかんないから。
You don't know yet! We still don't know yet.
水着かまああああ… もう行かないで！やめて！
Swimwear or maaah... Don't go! Stop!
引きずり出さないで。船長から情報を引きずり出そうとしないで！
Don't drag it out of me. Don't try to drag information out of the Captain!
いやでもね、もう本当にこれ船長が勝手に宣伝してるんじゃなくて、これは公式からね、あの言われて宣言してるんで
It's not like the Captain is advertising on her own; I'm announcing this because the staff told me to.
もうこれは船長が勝手にやってるんじゃなく、本当に公式で全体で盛り上げていくホロライブサマーとなっております！
This is truly a Hololive Summer that the official team as a whole is hyping up!
ということでね、この配信の後に、
So with that said, after this stream,
公式サイトと、ティザ…あ、ここに、はい！ご覧ください！
the official site and the teaser... ah, right here, yes! Please take a look!
この配信の後に公式サイトとティザーモビーのフルバージョンが公開予定です！
After this stream, the official site and full teaser movie will be released!
はい、詳細はホロライブ公式ツイートをお待ちください！
Yes, please wait for the official Hololive tweet for details!
よーし、じゃちょっとホロライブサマーに向けて、よし、アップしてくぞ！
Alright, getting hyped for Hololive Summer—alright, let's pump it up!
行きます！出撃ー！バイバーイ！
Here we go! Sortie! Bye-bye!